I'm gonna be talking about how to make
an if statement in assembly it statement
to useful for haven't you program D
responsive depending on if the setup
conditions are true or false
alright so let's get started in my data
section I define a couple variables one
is X and one is y and I gave them to
some random values like 32 and 50 at the
same time I also made two variables
called a message 1 and message to these
will be displayed depending on the
result of our if statement all right so
even come down to the body of our main
of our program which is the text section
that's where our code lives and we don't
see arm say X turn printf which allows
us to access this C standard library so
we can print out to the screen as well
as we're going to make our program the
main label available externally so that
other people can see where our programs
start in this case the operating system
of VF define main and execute hi so
let's go ahead and set up our stack
frame
you
alright so we just set up a Star Trek
create the starter and I'm destroyed
start ringing alright so now let's
actually get into the heart of writing
an if statement and remember what we
basically want to do is pay attention to
this pseudocode do not say if let's
comment it out we want to say if X is
greater than Y that is greater than 1
then message 1 will be displayed else
message 2 will be displayed all right so
how do we do that well we have to use a
comparative statement the compare
statement basically does a subtraction
between x and y without actually saving
the results but instead it's such a
register and we use a register
concerning what the result was by using
the conditional jump stick target so we
can say compare actually first of all
we're going to have to move one of the
two variables into a register because we
can't compare two memory locations at
the same time so e^x will be D word move
the value stored in X into a X and while
we're at it let's go ahead and move Y
into a to be X register and these are
the standard register hair a is for the
accumulation and B is for I think it
buffer or something that they're just
generic registers to hold data and so
here we're basically storing the value
of x into here and storing the value of
y into the exo trip and registers are
useful because they're right inside of
the CPU so it's faster to do operations
by having value stored in there all
right so let's go ahead and actually
start comparing so say compare ax
yes so this says compare what is X X is
32 and let's just make X to be 10 per se
so here we're going to say 10 is
compared with 50 or rather 50s in
paratime and you look and say jump if
Nicole and I jumped it greater than 2x
with y so jump is greater than X so this
tells us we're going to say jump if
greater jump if X is greater than Y so
we can say X is greater than Y this is
going to be a label that we're going to
make here in second let's say it's dots
and the dot notation is used to make a
local label inside of another label so
in this case the dots X is a label
that's local with respect to this main
label it's inside of me so X greater
than Y and we have to always put our
colon there and say now we're going to
display the message of moms we can say
push keyword the message or the message
run then call printf
and then we're gonna jump - done and
done is let me down here okay but um but
what only going to jump if X is greater
than Y but if it's not let's this will
be completely ignored and execution will
skip from here so right here and here we
can say okay well then push the second
message B word and when we're done
calling printf instead of going to
execution over here writing jump to done
you can come to done and done
walk the elk here and this just comes to
return and stop execution let's go to
the console and go ahead and execute
this method LS plus slash file input
file moon okay so I found in SM month SM
to the ASM a.m. all right says we have a
problem so let's go ahead and come back
over here put it to oh here we just
didn't jump jumps done and here we're
gonna save jump it's done so we save
that you come back and trial again okay
successful compiled so let's try to run
our program now so as it says over here
is playlist I'm running again Y is
greater than X the structure of the 50
so you can basically do a compare
statements compare the two values okay
of X&Y happy you into register because
we set registers are faster access to
the CPU okay and then what this
translates to here jump is greater this
says jump if X over here which is what X
is stored if X is greater than Y and if
it is greater than Y we'll can do a
jump straight to here but if it's not
greater than why we're going to skip
this condition jump because it's not
true and execute this body but then when
we're done printing the statement to the
screen we jump from here to here if we
didn't have the statement everything
gets executed for example let's go ahead
and comment this one ounce save up file
and execute see both statements get
executed because instead of jumping over
here everything got executed so we have
to have that uncommented out okay so
basic review again so we moved
everything into registers set up the
compare stating and jump if it's true
otherwise it is not sure everything gets
executed up until this point and when
we're done we just come over here and
remember that I said that you can make a
label with the dots label name and that
makes a label mobile with respect to
another label in this case these labels
are local with respect to the main label
and so yeah that's how to make an if
statement in assembly please remember to
rate and subscribe thank you